NITESH KUMAR

nk59627@gmail.com

S₇₃₀₄₂₇₁₅₉₉ / 9472716926

Thane (Mumbai), 421204

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nites h-kumar-91001a71

SKILLS

- Analytical skills
- Advance Excel
- Ability to track reports.
- Improvement plan understanding
- Process development
- Team member training
- Process optimization
- · Quality assurance
- Content management systems knowledge etc.

PROJECTS

Worked for Retail Marketplace (e-commerce sites) like

- Walmart Canada/International
- Croma
- Amazon
- Dell
- Tata Cliq (Electronic)
- Reliance Digital Electronics
- Flipkart
- Taglr
- Tillys
- Shopper Stop
- Casaone
- Arvind
- Sherwin Williams
- Noon
- Adorama

EDUCATION

Ranchi University • 08/2022 MBA Marketing & IT

Trident Academy of Technology Bhubaneswar, OD • 08/2016 **B.Tech:Mechanical Engineering**

Sobh Barachatti Gaya, BR *Intermediate* Science Education

St. john's high school Ranchi, JH *Matriculation*

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative Operations Specialist with talents in executing effective operating rhythms and management systems structures. Adept at analyzing, articulating, and solving various problems. Analytical and organized with the ability to work independently or as a part of a team. To grow in the domain of Operations and subsequent managerial functions with significant contributions in attaining valuable patents in my field of work in a progressive organization by strengthening my team, which dynamically works towards the success and growth of the organization.

WORK HISTORY

Rein Labs (Contexio) – Assistant Manager Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra • 05/2023 – Current

- Handling customer or management concerns
- Monitoring operating costs, budgets, and resources
- Managed a high workload and consistently achieved deadlines and production targets. Ensuring product quality.
- Managing employee work schedules, organizing daily activities, and ensuring schedules and objectives are met.
- Interacting with customers and learning their needs and specifications.

Rein Labs (Contexio) - Operations Team Leader Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra • 05/2019 - 04/2023

- Increased overall efficiency and productivity of the team by revamping jobs, schedules, and daily assignments.
- Helped set and manage objectives for quality, productivity, and compliance.
- Set schedules and oversaw daily workflow. Produced detailed reports outlining performance against benchmarks.
- Helped increase sales and customer retention by implementing new marketing and service strategies.
- Improved team efficiency and productivity by restructuring workflow and managing assignments.
- \bullet Tracked and analyzed reports to determine where improvements in business $\bmod d$ be made.
- Generated reports of findings to help management with making key decisions.

Rein Labs (Contexio) - Senior Research Analyst Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra • 05/2018 - 04/2019

- The Job involves capturing and structuring data to create product content for ecommerce organizations. Following set procedures/guidelines, using tools & and meeting relevant business objectives.
- Helped team meet regulatory requirements by coordinating documentation and filings.
- Collected and recorded data at various field sites for later assessment and data analysis.
- Reviewed and verified data before entering the database to enhance research quality and accuracy.
- Validated incoming data to check the accuracy and integrity of information while independently locating and correcting concerns.
- Took an active role in departmental meetings, engaging with all parties and transcribing detailed notes of plans, decisions, and options discussed.
- Developed macros, special formulas, and other actions to produce reliable and consistent statistical reviews.

eclerx - Junior Analyst Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra • 03/2017 - 05/2018 Transaction processing:

- Data Analysis of a complex product database in real-time.
- Database management services to activate/deactivate products.
- Maintenance of client portals with predefined business rules/guidelines.
- Guided divestiture activities, drawing on a deep understanding of various internal operational processes.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth	13-12-1992
Gender	Male
Languages Known	English/Hindi
Passport	Yes
Blood Group	O +ve
Marital Status	Married
Permanent Address	Nilam Kuti Old Market Road , Morabadi, Ranchi, Jharkhand 834008

DECLARATION:

I hereby, declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

DATE:

Nitesh Kumar
PLACE : Mumbai SIGNATURE